Guide to the G. Evelyn Hutchinson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1904-1991; Series I
  - Scientific American, 1948-1983 (Box 47, Folder 763)
  - Scott, Hugh, 1921-1960 (Box 47, Folder 764)
  - Scott-Craig, T. S. K., 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 765)
  - Sears, Paul, 1943-1971 (Box 47, Folder 766)
  - Sebestyén, Olga, 1967-1973 (Box 47, Folder 767)
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1971-1981 (Box 47, Folder 768)
  - Setlow, Jane and Richard, 1944-1979 (Box 47, Folder 769)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1937-1971 (Box 47, Folder 770)
  - Shadin, V. J., 1968 (Box 47, Folder 771)
  - Shapiro, Joseph, 1952-1985 (Box 47, Folder 772)
  - Shapley, Harlow, 1940-1950 (Box 47, Folder 773)
  - Sharp, Robert F., 1952-1954 (Box 47, Folder 774)
  - Shepard, Francis P., 1951-1958 (Box 47, Folder 775)
  - Shepard, Paul, 1951-1984 (Box 47, Folder 776)
  - Sheppard, C. W., 1945-1949 (Box 47, Folder 777)
  - Sherk, Truman, 1985-1988 (Box 47, Folder 778)
  - Shockley, William, 1966-1970 (Box 47, Folder 779)
  - Sigma Xi, 1958-1988 (Box 47, Folder 780)
  - Silver, Mary, 1981-1982 (Box 47, Folder 781)
  - Silvestri, F., 1933-1935 (Box 47, Folder 782)
  - Singer, Maxine and Stephanie, 1979-1988 (Box 47, Folder 783)
  - Sinnott, Edmund W., 1945-1988 (Box 47, Folder 784)
  - Slack, Nancy, 1970-1990 (Box 47, Folder 785)
  - Slobodkin, Lawrence B.
    - 1951-1958 (Box 47, Folder 786)
    - 1971-1988 (Box 48, Folder 787)
  - Smart, John, 1965-1983 (Box 48, Folder 788)
  - Smith, A. William, 1945-1958 (Box 48, Folder 789)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1930-1945, 1963-1984 (Box 48, Folder 790 - 791)
    See also: Series I, folders 716-719; Series II, folder 5
  - Soal, S. G., 1948-1950 (Box 48, Folder 792)
  - Societas Internationalis Limnologiae Theoreticae et Applicatae (Box 24, Folder 391-394)
  - Society for the Protection of Old Fishes, Inc., 1968-1990 (Box 48, Folder 793)
  - Society for the Scientific Study of Religion, 1955-1957 (Box 48, Folder 794)
  - Soil Science, 1944-1947 (Box 48, Folder 795)
  - Sokoloff, V. Peter, 1947-1957 (Box 48, Folder 796)
  - Sommer, Frank H., 1944-1948 (Box 48, Folder 797)
  - Spiesel, Christina Olson, 1975-1988 (Box 48, Folder 798)
  - Spitzer, Paul, 1975-1977 (Box 48, Folder 799)
  - Sprugel, Douglas, 1969-1973 (Box 48, Folder 800)
  - Stadnichenko, Taisia, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 801)
  - Stanley, Steven M., 1972-1978 (Box 48, Folder 802)
  - Stavin, Robert, 1970-1983 (Box 48, Folder 803)
  - Steinberg, Robert A., 1944 (Box 48, Folder 804)
  - Stella, Emilia, 1963-1988 (Box 48, Folder 805)
  - Stevelman, Faith Linda, 1982-1987 (Box 48, Folder 806)
  - Stoddart, David R., 1967-1979 (Box 48, Folder 807)
  - Strickler, J. Rudi, 1974-1983 (Box 48, Folder 808)
  - Strøm, Kaare Münster, 1945-1967 (Box 49, Folder 809)
  - Stross, Raymond G., 1961-1984 (Box 49, Folder 810)
  - Studies in Romanticism, 1976-1977 (Box 49, Folder 811)
  - Sugawara, Ken, 1951-1957 (Box 49, Folder 812)
  - Sullivan, Walter (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
  - Survey of Biological Progress, 1946-1949 (Box 49, Folder 813)
  - T, 1930-1990 (Box 49, Folder 814 - 820)
  - Tareen, Inam Ullah, 1971-1972 (Box 49, Folder 821)
  - Thienemann, August, 1931-1949 (Box 49, Folder 822)
  - Thorpe, William H., 1945-1986 (Box 49, Folder 823)
  - Tilley, C. E., 1945-1970 (Box 49, Folder 824)
  - Tongring, Nils, 1981-1986 (Box 49, Folder 825)
  - Tonolli, Vittorio and Livia Tonolli Pirocehi, 1949-1985 (Box 49, Folder 826)
  - Trelease, Sam F., 1944-1950 (Box 49, Folder 827)
  - Tressler, Willis L., 1941-1950 (Box 49, Folder 828)
  - Tsukada, Matsuo, 1964-1984 (Box 49, Folder 829)
  - Tunnicliffe, Verena, 1977-1983 (Box 49, Folder 830)
  - Turner, Harry J., 1938, 1967-1974 (Box 50, Folder 831)
  - Twombly, Saran, 1976-1991 (Box 50, Folder 832 - 833)
  - Tyler, Ruth, 1946-1953 (Box 50, Folder 834)
  - Tyler Prize (Box 25, Folder 405)
    See also: Series I, folder 405
  - U, 1934-1990 (Box 50, Folder 835 - 837)
  - Uéno, Masuzo, 1933-1951 (Box 50, Folder 838)
  - United States government, 1930-1985 (Box 50, Folder 839)
  - University of Cambridge, 1980-1981 (Box 50, Folder 840)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1942-1972 (Box 50, Folder 841)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1951-1972 (Box 50, Folder 842)
  - V, 1945-1985 (Box 50, Folder 843 - 845)
  - Vallentyne, John R.
    - 1948-1963 (Box 50, Folder 846)
    - 1965-1985 (Box 51, Folder 847)
  - Van Valen, Leigh, 1960-1977 (Box 51, Folder 848)
  - Vermeij, Edith Zipser and Geerat, 1968-1981 (Box 51, Folder 849)
  - Vernadsky, George, 1933-1948 (Box 51, Folder 850)
  - Verplank, Eva Low, 1950-1985 (Box 51, Folder 851)
  - Vogel, Beatrice, 1971-1993 (Box 51, Folder 852)
  - Vogt, William, 1946-1949 (Box 51, Folder 853)
  - W, 1930-1990 (Box 51, Folder 854 - 862)
  - Waggoner, Paul E., 1974-1987 (Box 51, Folder 863)
  - Walter, Erich A., 1956-1957 (Box 51, Folder 864)
  - Walter, Janet B., 1947-1948 (Box 52, Folder 865)
  - Walton, G. A., 1936-1939, 1961, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 866)
  - Warburg, Michael, 1963-1972 (Box 52, Folder 867)
  - Ward-Perkins, J. B., 1960-1970 (Box 52, Folder 868)
  - Ward's Natural Science Establishment, Inc., 1941-1948 (Box 52, Folder 869)
  - Ware, Caroline, 1954-1979 (Box 52, Folder 870)
  - Watson, Maxine, 1970-1991 (Box 52, Folder 871 - 872)
  - Watt, Ward, 1968-1990 (Box 52, Folder 873)
  - Weber, Neal A., 1931-1947 (Box 52, Folder 874)
  - Weiss, Paul, 1945-1952 (Box 52, Folder 875)
  - Werntz, Henry, 1956-1957 (Box 52, Folder 876)
  - Wetzel, Robert G. (Box 24, Folder 391-394)
    See also: Series I, folders 391-394
  - Wetzler, Richard E., 1948-1986 (Box 52, Folder 877)
  - Wheeler, Bernice, 1947-1949 (Box 52, Folder 878)
  - Whitehill, Walter Muir, 1969-1970 (Box 52, Folder 879)
  - Wildt, Rupert, 1940-1943, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 880)
  - Wilson, Edward O., 1962-1985 (Box 52, Folder 881)
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1950-1952 (Box 52, Folder 882)
    See also: Series I, folder 70
  - Winsor, Mary P., 1970-1983 (Box 52, Folder 883)
  - Wollack, Anne C., 1942-1946 (Box 52, Folder 884)
  - Wood, Christine M., 1972-1980 (Box 52, Folder 885)
  - Wulff, Janie Lea, 1981-1988 (Box 52, Folder 886)
  - X, 1981-1990 (Box 52, Folder 887)
  - Y, 1946-1977 (Box 52, Folder 888)
  - Yale Review, 1950-1989 (Box 53, Folder 889)
  - Yale University
    - General, 1945-1989 (Box 53, Folder 890)
    - Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory Advisory Committee, 1959-1964 (Box 53, Folder 891)
    - Committee on the Yale Herbarium, 1967-1968 (Box 53, Folder 892)
    - Conservation Program, 1952-1957 (Box 53, Folder 893)
    - Department of Biology, 1948-1991 (Box 53, Folder 894)
    - Graduate School, 1941-1973 (Box 53, Folder 895)
    - Library, 1923-1990 (Box 53, Folder 896 - 897)
    - President's Office, 1950-1989 (Box 53, Folder 898)
    - Provost's Office, 1945-1977 (Box 53, Folder 899 - 900)
    - Secretary's Office, 1935-1989 (Box 53, Folder 901)
    - Sheffield Scientific School, 1938-1946 (Box 53, Folder 902)
    - Treasurer's Office, 1944-1988 (Box 53, Folder 903)
    - Yale College. Dean's Office, 1945-1953 (Box 53, Folder 904)
    - Yale University Press
      - 1951-1973 (Box 53, Folder 905 - 907)
      - 1974-1989 (Box 54, Folder 908 - 913)
  - Silliman Luncheon Group, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 914)
  - Yapp, W. Brundson, 1972-1983 (Box 54, Folder 915)
  - Z, 1941-1985 (Box 54, Folder 916)
  - Zaret, Thomas M., 1965-1980 (Box 54, Folder 917)
  - Zinn, Donald J., 1941-1980 (Box 54, Folder 918)
  - Zobell, Claude E., 1945-1952 (Box 54, Folder 919)
  - Multiple greetings, 1950-1985, undated (Box 54, Folder 920)
  - Unidentified
    - First names only, 1934-1981 (Box 54, Folder 921)
    - Fragments of letters to unidentified recipients written during the Yale North India Expedition, 1932 (Box 54, Folder 922)
    - Illegible signatures, 1925-1986 (Box 54, Folder 923)
    - Fragments [no names], 1927-1983, undated (Box 54, Folder 924)
- Topical Files, 1927-1992; Series II
  This series is composed of correspondence, notes, reports, and other types of materials, which Hutchinson collected together by subject. The files are arranged alphabetically bu subject. The series reflects the wide and varied nature of Hutchinson's personal and professional interests and includes files on the Yale North India Expedition, various grant proposals on which Hutchinson worked, Yale curriculum materials, manuscripts by others, and Hutchinson's stamp collecting. Hutchinson's forays into public policy debates can be seen in his files on the Aldabra Islands in the Indian Ocean. Efforts of environmentalists such as Hutchinson helped secure this area as a nature preserve protecting giant tortoises. Hutchinson's early interest in geochemistry is evident in the titles of his various grant proposals but also in the typescript of the English translation of "Chemical Elements and Ions in the Crust of the Earth" by the noted Russian scientist Aleksandr Fersman. The series also includes a typescript of a work by the Russian microbiologist G. F. Gauze.
  - Aldabra Islands, 1966-1967 (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
  - Animals and Man [exhibits, lectures at Yale re the World Wildlife Fund and endangered species. Hutchinson spoke in place of Kenneth Clark], 1977-1978 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - British postal strike stamp collection, 1970-1992 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Chemical composition of sediments [committee records, grant proposals, correspondence, data], 1950-1955 (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
  - Christ Church, New Haven, 1988, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Fersman, Aleksandr [English typescript for "Chemical Elements and Ions in the Crust of the Earth"]
    - Pp. 1-303, undated (Box 55, Folder 9-11)
    - Pp. 304-761, undated (Box 56, Folder 12-16)
  - Gauze, G. F. [original typescript of "Problems of Evolution"], undated (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Grant proposals
    - Application to the Trustees of the Sheffield Fund for Grant in Aid of Limnological Problems, undated (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Graduate Research in Environmental Biology, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Hydrochemistry of Linsley Pond, North Branford, Connecticut, 1966 (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Integrated Area Grant in Ecology, [circa 1962] (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Limnological Work in Colorado, undated (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Outline of Proposed Investigation of Lake Tanganyika, undated (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Grants
    - General [correspondence with the National Science Foundation re administration], 1960-1971 (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Amino Acids in Lake Waters and Sediments [NSF G-14], 1952-1953 (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - Amino Acids in Lake Waters, Organisms and Sediments [NSF-B379], 1953-1957 (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Clay Components of Lake Sediments [NSF-G15606], 1930 (Box 56, Folder 27)
      See aslo: Series II, folder 36
    - Coherent Area Research Program in Ecology [NSF GB-12895], 1969-1972 (Box 56, Folder 28)
    - Diagenesis of Chlorophylls in Lake Sediments [NSF G-4090], 1957-1958 (Box 56, Folder 29)
    - Diagnostic Changes in Pigments in Laucustrine Sediments [NSF-G5686], 1958-1959 (Box 56, Folder 30)
    - Graduate Research in Environmental Biology [NSF GB5653], 1966 (Box 56, Folder 31)
    - Paleolimnological Studies in Italian Lakes [NSF-G8916], 1959-1960 (Box 57, Folder 32)
    - Paleolimnology and History [NSF GB-12894; renewal GB-28081], 1969-1973 (Box 57, Folder 33-34)
    - Paleolimnology and History [NSF BMS75-14270, BMS71-00830]; Paleoecological Studies [NSF BMS 76-01620], 1974-1978 (Box 57, Folder 35)
    - NSF-G17831, 1961-1962 (Box 57, Folder 36)
  - MacArthur, Robert
    - National Medal of Science, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 37)
    - Symposium and memorial volume, 1973 1975 (Box 57, Folder 38)
  - Peabody Museum of Natural History directorship, 1963 1988 (Box 57, Folder 39)
  - Stone circles, 1958, 1968- 1973 (Box 57, Folder 40)
  - Tokharian inscription on the Tangste rock, 1982-1985 (Box 57, Folder 41)
  - Yale North India Expedition
    - Notes, reports, 1927, 1930-1936 (Box 57, Folder 42-44)
    - Field books, notebooks, 1927, 1930-1936 (Box 58, Folder 45-48)
  - Yale University
    - Biogeochemistry course, 1973, undated (Box 58, Folder 49)
    - Ecology program, [circa 1965-1987] (Box 58, Folder 50)
    - Geochronometric Laboratory, 1953-1958 (Box 58, Folder 51)
    - Geography program, 1941, undated (Box 58, Folder 52)
    - "Science III" course, undated (Box 58, Folder 53)
- Research and Writings, 1922-1991; Series III
  This series includes materials related to Hutchinson's research and writings. They are organized in sections: articles and essays; books; lectures and speeches; notes; research notebooks; and writings, unpublished. The series does not include research grant proposals, which are in Series II. It also does not include copies of any of Hutchinson's publications, which are widely available. Hutchinson compiled a listing of his published works, other than books, as part of the process of creating bound volumes of his "Collected Papers." These bound volumes are available in the Yale University Kline Science Library. Most of the separately published articles and pamphlets that the volumes contain would also be available in the original journals.
  The listing for the contents of the "Collected Papers" served as an authority for organizing materials in the first section in the series, articles and essays. There are far more titles on the list than are represented by the materials in the section. The early years of Hutchinson's career are particularly under represented. Since the volumes of "Collected Papers" do not include lectures and speeches, there is a separate section for typescripts and notes for these. They are arranged in chronological order according to delivery date. Where known the title is given, but many speeches are identified only by place of delivery, event, or topic.
  Materials associated with other titles not found on the list of "Collected Papers" are organized in the Writings, unpublished section. It is possible that some manuscripts in this section may be chapter drafts or other sections of a larger work which were renamed in the later published version. Other materials may be for "Marginalia" columns, reports, or possibly lectures. Folder descriptions in which the title is enclosed in quote marks indicate either a title found on the manuscript or in Hutchinson's handwriting on the original Folder. Other Folder headings give the general topic of the manuscript. Folders are arranged alphabetically by title or topic, with a few Folders of material arranged by type at the end of the section.
  More materials of similar appearance but without any title are arranged under the heading "Loose pages." These handwritten or typed pages appear to be drafts of sections or fragments of writings. Often the pages are numbered sequentially, but the manuscript commences on a page other than 1. Because the pages could not be attributed to a particular work they have been left as found in seemingly random order. Included in some Folders are photocopies of the original Folders on which Hutchinson scrawled notes. These have been retained in an effort to help the researcher identify the contents of the Folder. Some of these proved to be identification of only the first item in the Folder and not of other materials that were filed farther on. It is quite possible that any Folder may contain pages from unrelated manuscripts, either published or unpublished. There may also be pages that more closely resemble materials found in the notes section of research materials. This has led to a larger than usual amount of material which has been tentatively identified, left unidentified, or possibly misidentified.
  The collected data and observations in the sections Notes and Research notebooks suggest the breadth of Hutchinson's scientific interests including butterflies, aquatic insects, guano found on islands, the archaeology of Guernsey, various lakes, and biogeochemistry. The Notes section includes materials similar in appearance to the "Loose pages." These are arranged by topic, and some of this material is associated with courses Hutchinson gave during his long teaching career.
  The section Books includes drafts and notes for Hutchinson's many books. The manuscripts for the A Treatise on Limnology, the magnum opus which Hutchinson published in four volumes over a period of more than thirty years, are the most voluminous, with those for the last volume being the most extensive as well as the least well organized. The handwritten manuscripts and typescripts reflect the development of Hutchinson's ideas for the work over many years. In the evolution, he created numerous versions for many sections, interleaving pages from handwritten drafts with subsequent typed material. Many pages are heavily annotated and some bear as many as three different chapter numbers with as many different page numbers.
  Because serious work to complete the fourth volume began when Hutchinson was already in his eighties, he needed the assistance of numerous individuals, particularly Yvette Edmondson and Anna Aschenbach. The files reflect their efforts to decipher Hutchinson's editorial comments and include some correspondence between them, which was generated in the process. Since most of the drafts are undated, the files for this volume could not be organized to trace the development of each chapter, and the files are undifferentiated beyond the form of the material as typescript or handwritten.
  - Articles and essays
    - The Branchial Gland of the Cephalopoda-A Possible Endocrine Organ, 1928 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - "Two Biological Aspects of Psycho analytic Theory", 1930 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Yale North India Expedition. Report on Amphipod Crustacea of the Genus, 1934 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - "Studies on Connecticut Lake Sediments. II. Chemical Analyses of a Core from Linsley Pond, North Branford.", 1940 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - "Biological Accumulators of Aluminum", 1943 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - "Marginalia", 1943-1955, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 6-10)
    - "Shepherd Rockeries", 1943 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - "Problems of Biogeochemistry, II. Introduction: The Fundamental Matter energy Difference between the Living and the Inert Natural Bodies of the Biosphere", 1944 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - "Aluminum in Soils, Plants, and Animals", 1945 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - "Note on a Specimen of Silk from Dura", 1945 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - "Biochemical Observations on Asterias forbesi", 1946 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - "A Direct Demonstration of the Phosphorous Cycle in a Small Lake", 1947 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - "A Note on the Theory of Competition between Two Social Species", 1947 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - "The Problems of Oceanic Geochemistry", 1947 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - "Circular Causal Systems in Ecology", 1948 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - "On Living in the Biosphere", 1948 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - "Ecological Studies on Populations", 1949 (Box 59, Folder 21-22)
    - "Limnological Studies of Connecticut. IX. A Quantitative Radiochemical Study of the Phosphorus Cycle in Linsley Pond", 1950 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - "Notes on the Functions of a University", 1950 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - "On the Rate of Passive Sinking of Daphnia", 1950 (Box 60, Folder 25)
    - "Survey of Contemporary Knowledge of Biogeochemistry. III. The Biogeochemistry of Vertebrate Excretion"
      - 1950 (Box 60, Folder 26-36)
      - 1950 (Box 61, Folder 37-44)
    - "Copepodology for the Ornithologist", 1951 (Box 61, Folder 45)
    - "The Possible Role of Sexual Selection in the Etiology of Endemic Goiter", 1951 (Box 61, Folder 46)
    - Reviews: The Sensory World of the Bee; Die Binnengewässer Bd.; The Lovers of the Card Index Cards, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 47)
    - "The Biogeochemistry of Phosphorous", 1952 (Box 61, Folder 48)
    - "Methodology and Value in the Natural Sciences in Relation to Certain Religious Concepts", 1952 (Box 61, Folder 49)
    - "The Concept of Pattern in Ecology", 1953 (Box 61, Folder 50)
    - Reviews: The Origin and History of British Fauna; Reports of the Swedish Deep Sea Expedition, 1947-1948, 1953 (Box 61, Folder 51)
    - "The Biochemistry of the Terrestrial Atmosphere", 1954 (Box 61, Folder 52)
    - "Gene Dispersal and Ethology of the Rhinocerotidae", 1954 (Box 62, Folder 53)
    - "The Natural C14 contents of Materials from Hard water Lakes", 1954 (Box 62, Folder 54)
    - "Scientific Language and Religious Faith", 1954 (Box 62, Folder 55)
    - Review: The Challenge of Man's Future, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 56)
    - "The Enchanted Voyage", 1955 (Box 62, Folder 57)
    - "New Approaches to the Study of Lake Sediments", 1955 (Box 62, Folder 58)
    - "On the Nickel, Cobalt, and Copper Contents of Deep sea Sediments", 1955 (Box 62, Folder 59)
    - "Concluding Remarks", 1957 (Box 62, Folder 60)
    - "Future of Marine Paleoecology", 1957 (Box 62, Folder 61)
    - "Manganese Deposition and Deep Water Movements in the Caribbean", 1958 (Box 62, Folder 62)
    - "Homage to Santa Rosalia or Why Are There So Many Kinds of Animals?", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 63)
    - "Il Concetto Moderno di Nicchia Ecologica", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 64)
    - "On the Theoretical Significance of Aggressive Neglect in Interspecific Competition", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 65)
    - "The Pageant of the Animal Kingdom", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 66)
    - "The Role of the Museum in Teaching and Research", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 67)
    - "A Speculative Consideration of Certain Possible Forms of Sexual Selection in Man", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 68)
    - "A Theoretical Ecological Model of Size Distributions Among Species of Animals", 1959 (Box 62, Folder 69)
    - "John Farquhar Fulton", 1960 (Box 62, Folder 70)
    - "Landscape with Animals: Zoology's Romantic Story", 1960 (Box 62, Folder 71)
    - "A Set of Informed Guesses", 1960 (Box 62, Folder 72)
    - "The Biologist Poses Some Problems", 1961 (Box 62, Folder 73)
    - "Fifty Years of Man in the Zoo", 1961 (Box 62, Folder 74)
    - "The Paradox of the Plankton", 1961 (Box 62, Folder 75)
    - Review: Evolution above the Species Level, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 76)
    - "An Apparent Lunar Periodicity in the Sexual Cycle of Certain Prosimians", 1962 (Box 62, Folder 77)
    - "Chemical Examination of a Core from Lake Zeribar, Iran", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 78)
    - "The Cream in the Gooseberry Fool", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 79)
    - El Bajo de Santa Fé, 1963 (Box 62, Folder 80)
    - "Is an Electron Smaller than a Dream?", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 81)
    - "Natural Selection, Social Organization, Hairlessness, and the Australopithecine Canine", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 82)
    - "The Naturalist as an Art Critic", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 83)
    - "A Note on the Polymorphism of Philaenus spumarius", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 84)
    - "The Prospect before Us", 1963 (Box 62, Folder 85)
    - "Cultural Eutrophication in Lado di Monterosi during Roman Antiquity", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 86)
    - "Cypria petenensis, a New Name for the Ostracod Cyria pelagica Brehm 1932", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 87)
    - "The Influence of the Environment", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 88)
    - "The Lacustrine Microcosm Reconsidered", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 89)
    - "Notes on Ecological Principles Easily Seen in the Hall of Southern New England Natural History", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 90)
    - "On Flinia Terminalis (Plate) and F. Pejleri Sp. N. (Rotatoria: Family Testudinellidae)", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 91)
    - "Eretima Gosse 1886 (? Rotatoria) Proposed Suppression of this Generic Name under the Plenary Powers", 1965 (Box 63, Folder 92)
    - "A General Account of the Basin and the Chemistry and Mineralogy of the Sediment Core", 1966 (Box 63, Folder 93)
    - "On Being a Meter and a Half Long", 1966 (Box 63, Folder 94)
    - "The Sensory Aspects of Taxonomy, Pleiotropism, and the Kinds of Manifest Evolution", 1966 (Box 63, Folder 95)
    - "To Save Baikal", 1966 (Box 63, Folder 96)